Mello, Michael; Papers apap287
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Davidson James, 1970-1993; 2; 2.2 cubic ft.
  - James v. Singletary -USCA, 11th Circuit, 1993 (Box 4 (2-Davidson James), Folder 2)
  - James v. Singletary - USSC, 1993 (Box 5 (2-Davidson James), Folder 1)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit, Undated (Box 5 (2-Davidson James), Folder 2)
- Bennie Demps, 1977-1990; 3; 1.8 cubic ft.
  This series contains legal material and correspondence related to the trials of Bennie Demps.
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC ( 1 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 1)
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC ( 2 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 3)
  - Demps-Presentence Investigation, 1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 4)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 1 of 4), 1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 5)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 2 of 4), 1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 6)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 3 of 4), 1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 7)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 4 of 4), 1978 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 8)
  - Demps - Research, 1978; 1980; 1983-1988; Undated (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 9)
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC, 1979-1981 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 10)
  - Demps v. Wainwright-USCA, 5th Circuit, 1980 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 11)
  - Demps v. Wainwright- USDC, M. FL, 1980 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 12)
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC, 1981 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 13)
  - Demps v. Florida- US SC, 1981 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 14)
  - Demps - Death Warrants, 1982; 1987 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 15)
  - Demps - Psychological Evaluation [ Restricted], 1982 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 16)
  - Demps v. Florida- FL SC, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 17)
  - Demps v. Wainwright - USDC, M. FL, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 18)
  - Demps v. Wainwright- US SC, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 19)
  - Florida v. Demps - 10th Circuit, FL, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 20)
  - Demps v. Florida- FL SC, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 21)
  - Demps v. Wainwright- USDC, M. FL, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 22)
  - Demps v. Wainwright-USCA, 11th Circuit, 1986 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 23)
  - Demps v. Dugger- FLSC, 1987 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 24)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 1 of 4), 1987 (Box 1 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 25)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 2 of 4), 1987 (Box 2 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 1)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 3 of 4), 1987 (Box 2 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 2)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 4 of 4), 1987 (Box 2 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 3)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USSC, 1987 (Box 2 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 4)
  - Demps v. Wainwright-USCA, 11th Circuit, 1987 (Box 2 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 5)
  - Florida v. Demps - 8th Circuit, FL, 1987 (Box 2 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 1)
  - Demps v. Dugger- USCA, 11th Circuit ( 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 2)
  - Demps v. Dugger- USCA, 11th Circuit ( 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 4)
  - Demps- Affidavit, 1989 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 5)
  - Demps v. Dugger- USCA, 11th Circuit, 1989 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 6)
  - Demps v. Dugger- USSA, 1989-1990 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 9)
  - Demps - Notes, Undated (Box 3 (3-Bennie Demps), Folder 10)
- Nollie Lee Martin, 1979-1987; 4; 1 cubic ft.
  This series contains legal material, correspondence, notes, research files, and correspondence related to the trials of Nollie Lee Martin.
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 1 of 6), 1979 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 1)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 2 of 6), 1979 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 2)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 3 of 6), 1979 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 3)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 4 of 6), 1979 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 4)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 5 of 6), 1979 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 5)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 6 of 6), 1979 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 6)
  - Martin v. Florida- FLSC, 1981 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 7)
  - Martin v. Florida- FLSC, 1984 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 8)
  - Martin - Disciplinary Report Worksheet, 1985 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 9)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- FLSC ( 1 of 2), 1986 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 10)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- FLSC ( 2 of 2), 1986 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 11)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- USSC, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 13)
  - Florida v. Martin - 8th Circuit, FL, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 14)
  - Martin v. Dugger- FLSC, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 15)
  - Martin v. Dugger- USDC, S. FL ( 1 of 2), 1987 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 16)
  - Martin v. Dugger- USDL, S. FL ( 2 of 2), 1982 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 17)
  - Martin v. Dugger- USSC, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 18)
  - Martin v. Florida- FLSC, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 19)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- Research, 1987; Undated (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 20)
  - Martin - Unlabeled Appendix, ca. 1987 (Box 1 (4-Nollie Lee Martin), Folder 21)
- General Case Files, 1977-2004; 5; 10.2 cubic ft.
  The series is organized alphabetically by the name of the client.
  This series is made up of legal material and correspondence for cases on which Michael Mello may have had some connection; as counsel, informal advisor, or cases for which he was hired to write Amicus Curiae. Some of the more prominent cases represented in this series include Rolando Cruz, Alvin Ford, Joseph M. Giarratano, and Michael Lambrix.
  - Aubrey Dennis Adams, 1985-1989 (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Aubrey Dennis Adams, 1985-1989 (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Jerome M. Allen, 1993 (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Phillip Alexander Atkins, 1992 (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Omar Blanco, 1986 (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 1 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 2 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 3 of 10), 1983-1984; 1982-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 4 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 5 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 6 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 7 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 8 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 9 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 10 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 15)
  - Theodore Robert Bundy, 1988 (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 16)
  - Raymond Robert Clark, 1987-1988; 1990 (Box 1 (5-General Case Files), Folder 17)
  - William Carl Coleman, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Rolando Cruz, ca. 1988; 1993 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - David Ross Delap, S.R, 1987; 1989 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Ernest Charles Dawns, 1987 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - William Dvane Elledge, 1983; 1987 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - William Eutzy, 1989-1990 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Alvin Bernad Ford, 1982-1988 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Alvin Bernad Ford, 1982-1988 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Charles Kenneth Foster, 1987; 1992 (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 1 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 2 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 3 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 4 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 5 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 6 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 15)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 7 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 16)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 8 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-General Case Files), Folder 17)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 1 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 2 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 3 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 4 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 5 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 6 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 7 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 8 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 9 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 10 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 11 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 12 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 13 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Demetrius Gathers, 1988-1989 (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 3 (5-General Case Files), Folder 15)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Freddie Lee Hall, 1986-1989 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Freddie Lee Hall, 1986-1989 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Lenson Hargrave, 1987 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1986-1990 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1986-1990 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1986-1990 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1990 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1990 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Leonel Torres Herrera, ca. 1992; 1993 (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 1 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 2 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 3 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 4 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 5 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 6 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 7 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 8 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Paul Jenings Hill, 2003 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - James Earnest Hitchcock, 1984-1986 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Carl Jackson, 1988; 1990 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Larry Joe Johnson, 1988; 1990 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Samuel Bice Johnson, 1987 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 1 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 2 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 3 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 4 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 5 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 15)
  - Edward D. Kennedy, 1992; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 16)
  - Edward Dean Kennedy - Artwork, Undated (Flat-file 33)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 1 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 17)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 2 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 6 (5-General Case Files), Folder 18)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 3 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 4 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 5 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 6 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 7 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 8 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 9 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 10 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 11 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 12 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 13 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 14 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 15 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 16 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 17 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7 (5-General Case Files), Folder 15)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 18 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - George Lemon, 1988 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Bobby Earl Lusk, 1989-1991; 1993 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Paul Edward Magill, 1985-1986 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Paul Edward Magill, 1985-1986 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Larry Eugene Mann, 1986-1987 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Larry Eugene Mann, 1986-1987 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Frank Basil McFarland, 1993-1994 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Donald Ray Middlebrooks, 1992-1993 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Ralph Mills, 1987-1988 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Ralph Mills, 1987-1988 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Ralph Mills, 1987-1988 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Robert Lacy Parker, 1991 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Thomas Pitera, 1991 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Thomas Pitera, 1991 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 15)
  - Thomas Pitera, 1992 (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 16)
  - Raleigh Porter, 1991; Undated (Box 8 (5-General Case Files), Folder 17)
  - Ricky Bernard Roberts, 1993 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - Jerry Layne Rogers, 1993 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Dan Edward Routly, 1996 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Robert Sawyer, 1989-1991 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Christopher Simmons, 1997; 2003-2004 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 7)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 8)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 9)
  - Frank Elijah Smith, 1990 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 10)
  - Jimmy Lee Smith, 1987-1989 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 11)
  - Dennis Sochor, 1992-1993 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 12)
  - Kevin N. Stanford, 1988-1989 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 13)
  - Raymound R. Stone, 1986-1987 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 14)
  - Raymound R. Stone, 1986-1987 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 15)
  - Ronald J. Straight, 1981; 1986 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 16)
  - Robert Austin Sullivan, 1983 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 17)
  - Jesse Joseph Tafero, 1988-1989 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 18)
  - William Wayne Thompson, 1986-1988 (Box 9 (5-General Case Files), Folder 19)
  - William Wayne Thompson, 1986-1988 (Box 10 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - William Wayne Thompson, 1986-1988 (Box 10 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - Manuel Valle, 1990 (Box 10 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - David William Ware ( 1 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989 (Box 10 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - David William Ware ( 2 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 10 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - David William Ware ( 3 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 10 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - David William Ware ( 4 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 11 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
  - David William Ware ( 5 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 11 (5-General Case Files), Folder 2)
  - David William Ware ( 6 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 11 (5-General Case Files), Folder 3)
  - Jerome Washington, 1992 (Box 11 (5-General Case Files), Folder 4)
  - Johnny Watkins, 1986 (Box 11 (5-General Case Files), Folder 5)
  - Frank Robert West, 1991-1992 (Box 11 (5-General Case Files), Folder 6)
  - Frank Robert West, 1991-1992 (Box 12 (5-General Case Files), Folder 1)
- Publications, 1979-2006; 6; 4.4 cubic ft.
  This series is organized alphabetically by publication.
  This series contains drafts of Mellos various publications, correspondence concerning those publications, copies of newspaper and magazine articles by or about Michael Mello, and advertising and publicity related to his publications. Michael Mello published 6 books, as well as numerous book chapters, journal and newspaper articles, many of which covered similar topics and themes.
  Researchers should note that the original arrangement of this series was minimal. Many of Michael Mellos publications cover similar topics or were revised and used for different publication types. For instance, a book chapter may be a revised version of a previously published journal articles. When possible the archivist has titled the folder to reflect which publication for which the document refers, however, this was not always possible.
  - "Adhering to our views: Brennan and Marshall and the Relentless Dissent to Death as a Punishment" by Michael Mello- Florida State University Law Review, Winter, 1995 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Against the Death Penalty - Galley Proofs, ca. 1995 (Flat-file 1)
  - Against the Death Penalty - Galley Proofs in Negatives, ca. 1995 (Flat-file 2)
  - Against the Death Penalty: The Relantless Dissents of Justices Brennan and Marshall- Order Form, Undated (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 2)
  - "Another Attorney for Life" b Michael Mello, 1989 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 3)
  - "Ariadne's Provisions: A 'Clue of Thread' to the Intricacies of Procedural Default, Adequate and Independent State Grounds, and Florida's Death Penalty" by Ruthann Robson and Michael Mello- California Law Review, 1988 January (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Borders Book Signing Event, 2000 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 5)
  - " Brief of the National Legal Aid and Detender Association, As Amicus Curiae in support of Respondent in Roper v. Simmons" by Michael Mello- Whittie, Journal of Child and Family Advocacy, Spring, 2006 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (1 of 4), 2000 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (2 of 4), 2000 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (3 of 4), 2000 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (4 of 4), 2000 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 10)
  - "'Cold as a Lizard and Ambitious as Lucifer': The Questions I am most Frequently Asked about the unabomber," by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Bulletin, 2000 January- February (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 11)
  - " The Color of Justice: Race, Class, and Capital Punishment in the United States", 2005 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 14)
  - " Counseling Kaczynski"- The National Jurist, 1999 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 15)
  - "' Dear Deanna': A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death"- Draft, 1993 December 23 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 16)
  - " Dear Laura": A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death- Draft (1 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 17)
  - " Dear Laura": A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death- Draft (2 or 2), ca.1995 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 18)
  - " Dead Reckoning: The Duty of Scholarship and the Ethics of Conscientous Abstention From Death Raw Representation" by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Bulletin, 1999 September- October (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 19)